Two of the major concepts involved in Flexbox or the axis and the direction.
من المفاهيم الأساسية في «فليكس بوكس»: المحور والاتجاه.
The Flexbox model relies on two axis.
يعتمد نموذج الصندوق المرن «فليكس بوكس» على محورين.
The main axis is defined by flex direction which has four possible values: row,
يُعرّف المحور الرئيسي بالاتجاه المرن، وله أربع قيم ممكنة هي: الصف،
row reverse, column, and column reverse.
وعكس الصف، والعمود، وعكس العمود.
The two row settings will create the main access horizontally or
يقوم الإعدادان المخصصان للصفوف بإنشاء المحور الرئيسي أفقيًا أو بشكل
inline while the two column settings will create
خطي، أم إعدادات الأعمدة تنشئ
the main access vertically or block direction.
المحور الرئيسي عموديًا أو بشكل طولي.
This means that whichever access is not the main access will be our alternate access.
ويعني ذلك أننا سنعتبر المحور غير الرئيسي بأنه المحور البديل.
The axis determined the flow of your content.
يحدد المحور تدفق المحتوى.
You can think of this as being either rows or columns,
يمكننا التفكير بذلك إما بأخذ الصفوف أو الأعمدة بالاعتبار،
and they will be determinant when you start aligning and
وستصبح محددة للمحتوى عندما تبدأ بمحاذاة
justifying content within a flex container.
وضبط المحتوى ضمن حاوية مرنة.
Now that we've talked about axis and
والآن بعد أن تحدثنا عن المحور
direction as well as looking at the row and column settings,
والاتجاه وعن إعدادات الصف والعمود،
let's combine it all and take a quick look together and see if we can
لنرَ كيف يمكننا استخدامهما معًا ونتعرف إلى
understand exactly what's going on with these directions and these different axis.
ما يحدث للاتجاهات والمحاور المختلفة.